now let's do a quiz on the relationship
between dependencies and Hazards let's
say that we have a three-stage pipeline
where here we are fetching and decoding
the instruction here we're reading the
register inputs that we need and doing
the AL operation and here we are
accessing the memory and then writing
the result to the register for an early
operation we just write to the register
let's say that we have these four
instructions the first one is producing
R1 and the next three are using it and I
can tell you that these three
dependencies are the only dependencies
that exist in this program the question
for you is whether there is a dependence
from the ad to this instruction and
whether that dependence is a hazard put
a check mark into these six boxes
depending on which one has a dependence
and which one of these dependences is a
hazard